annoying general how to not be offended
what others are doing [Music]
[Music]
another thing strange before basically
because it's you get offended by people
by your mind but if the mind was if you
were able to keep your mind in check
then the insult will just come and go
and you wouldn't be affected by it but
you can't expect to be able to keep your
mind in check if your body hasn't been
kept in check and your speech hasn't
good question so that's right that's
what it's a hard thing to do in a way
because people are generally impatient
so yeah no problem they want to fix but
I tell them but in order to fix it in
you to start building the basis for it
for the for the fix for the solution
because if you are if you were a very
strong person in regard to your own
desires they usually move people left
and right if you if you have if you have
confidence if you have confidence comes
from the restraint from being able to
say no to yourself then yeah you
wouldn't lose perspective even when
others basically abuse you verbally or
even physically like you wouldn't the
mind will not feel beaten because of it
because it's it's basically the mind
gives in the mind makes itself insulted
and affected by
because those the world's I mean the
physical actions can they stop with your
body the world the words they stop at a
level of speech but then it's the mind
picks it up resist it doesn't want it
rates it gives into your bill an account
of it or similar say someone calls you
you get offended if you were not if you
were not clear about you don't use
beforehand if you are holding on to them
both ladies unwholesome regions such as
in the sense of identity or because you
can see yourself as an intelligent
person smart person select reservation
or just general insecure and then you
kind of find solace in in in conviction
faith and then you solve the challenges
that you did touch struck right right in
your core but if you've you have used
the products for free strength and
wisdom nobody can the whole world can
disagree with it like you wouldn't be
able to be reflected by because he's
nothing wrong with it it's not based on
how unwholesome doesn't harm anyone and
it frees you from sufferings right there
right now sorry right right right here
now in a sense of that you have a direct
verification that you are not pulled and
controlled by your own desires anymore
as much as you used to be which is
there's already that sense of confidence
oh yeah no this works no no people can
come and tell you no that doesn't work
that's ridiculous that's just nonsense
you won't make a difference to because
actually you've seen it work so you were
the only the only conclusion we are they
don't talk about because if they were to
know they would agree with this it's
universally right
suta from desire so if you if you have
that kind of clarity internally then
insults you won't be able to insult you
but if somebody says something in your
world he's evil
or they wouldn't necessarily cause
earlier and then you wouldn't because
you're not following well you wouldn't
lose your own perspective which means
you will be able actually to hear what
they are saying even if it's a complete
ridiculous nonsense insult you would
still be able to hear it because you're
not immediately automatically on a
defensive and then sometimes you
actually here's applying there I mean
he's completely wrong because he's full
of ill-will and comes from the wrong
place but that's not my problem but the
content of what he was saying yeah I
made a mistake and that's it you
wouldn't be able to take it personally
you wouldn't be able to job come in you
wouldn't be able to take it personal and
that's that's the problem people cannot
help but take what people's mind cannot
help but take whatever comes their ways
personally and then immediately end up
either rejoicing in praise or defending
against the blame and attacking and
fearing blame as well even if it's
completely groundless and ridiculous
there's still fear just the phenomenon
of blame
doesn't matter by whom
what for if it could live like if it's
just at the fabrication is nobody truth
doesn't matter they'll still try to
avoid blame for the sacred because they
fear it but they don't have that clarity
and transparency and control over their
own mind to not be able to jump in it in
that irrational manner
what about things like that no no you
like the weather well again it's the
same similar attitude into slightly more
slightly more soccer I know it's a again
it is a home of you resisting things
that are not really your to go example
the weather require you annoyed because
you have desires it require a good
weather and while those desires are
present the bad weather is causing the
discrepancy that's making you know you
wanna get a little early but can you get
rid of the bed that's why it's important
to recognize that that discrepancy is
causing you to suffer if it is then you
will recognize that the way that you can
remove that suffering is removing
discrepancy so if you can't change the
weather you can't change the external
circumstances in the nature which means
what you can treat change what you what
you want you at the time change entities
if you remove the designers requiring
sunny day
if you were just you had a desire to
just stay in if you're annoyed it's
gotta be a reason and that reason is
that that basically what makes that
discrepancy so you can either continue
blaming the circumstances blame the
weather blame the world blame the other
people or recognize that that is
inevitable and that's not where the
suffering is routed know that
discrepancy it's rooted in things that
you can say no to which is your own
desire but people take that for granted
so they never want to say no to the no
desire which is why it's always someone
else's puzzles or whatever suffering
arises because of this so because of
that it's never because oh I crave and I
cause discrepancy with my desires and as
a result of that you have to suffer
there is no other cause of suffering
like that as if craving is sometimes
suffering or something no whenever the
suffering is because the discrepancy
called the claiming happiness not like
more or less or a bit later no to the
extent it is a discrepancy to that
extent there is suffering and that
discrepancy with craving is either
trying to prolong that which doesn't
last as long trying to get rid of that
which lasts school
right right then you see them you sort
of think that they know those all of
those things are management of the
problem none of them management cannot approach
none of them management cannot approach
are true to the problem can only manage
it which means it requires it so yes in
the beginning when there is absolutely
you don't really like confusion you
don't know what to do so then your
management can offer some sort of help
but it's a mistake to regard management
as as a way of practicing towards
uprooting the problem altogether
shi-wan arise over again good management
just covers up just bills with it which
means then the next one comes you have
two minute which means that's not
freedom when you need to do something
whenever this this occurs I need to go
through these motions I need to do it
sooner or later is gonna get too much
that's the definition of a burger duty
so you won't train at the development of
mind or meditation and practice whereby
you don't have to do anything on account
of suffering except you see and you
cannot not see it if you're just mindful
you always see it because your money and
suffering is something that universally
you cannot be oblivious to which means
all you have to do is remain mindful and
see the suffering and then the suffering
losses I mean if you're doing things
rightly then same suffering will means
approaching the suffering because you
understood it but management of
suffering does not mean updating of
suffering so management of of annoyance
does not make you impenetrable to future
annoyance and you know that you might
become very skilled manager and be able
to deal with these things very quickly
but still you need to deal with them
which means you're affected in the first
place and freedom of it freedom from it
is when you're not affected even in the
first place so that's the difference
when it comes to freeing yourself from
suffering don't confuse management of it
as the way out of it ultimately it's not
the way out of it is understanding the
nature of it where by having suffering a
reason means you're free from it Oh
simply pulled heavy suffering reason
means it can't touch you and arising of
suffering just reminds you did you're
free of suffering which means there is
no suffering